<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:atom='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom'>
<channel>
<atom:link href='http://https://clojure-data-science-course.github.io' rel='self' type='application/rss+xml'/>
<title>
Clojure Data Science Course
</title>
<link>
http://https://clojure-data-science-course.github.io
</link>
<description>
Information and course materials for the clojure data science course running in Tel Aviv
</description>
<lastBuildDate>
Sat, 15 Dec 2018 02:37:40 +0200
</lastBuildDate>
<generator>
clj-rss
</generator>
<item>
<guid>
http://https://clojure-data-science-course.github.io/posts-output/2018-12-15-notes-from-the-first-meeting/
</guid>
<link>
http://https://clojure-data-science-course.github.io/posts-output/2018-12-15-notes-from-the-first-meeting/
</link>
<title>
Notes from the First Meeting
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;On the first meetings of the course, we introduced ourselves and had some light introduction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;&lt;a href='https://www.meetup.com/Clojure-Israel/events/255927870/'&gt;Meeting A1&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#95;-&amp;#95;nov&amp;#95;25th&amp;#95;2018&quot;&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.meetup.com/Clojure-Israel/events/255927870/'&gt;Meeting A1&lt;/a&gt; - Nov 25th 2018&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was the first meeting of &lt;strong&gt;Group A&lt;/strong&gt; - clojure for data scientists.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We began with a broad introduction to Clojure by Matan Safriel. You can find his presentation &lt;a href='https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1kJHsDoX6hDlocW7XP-lNhtjDbtED0E7tjgss8QaXdUE/edit#slide=id.g4949e067d5_0_1'&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then everybody introduced themselves, and we discussed our &lt;a href='http://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://github.com/clojure-data-science-course/talks/blob/master/talk1/talk.html'&gt;wishes, challanges and goals&lt;/a&gt; for the course.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We continued to play a little with Clojure, and then looked into some use case example - scraping data from a wikipedia page, and visualizing the results. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We used Jupyter for the example, but after the meeting we decided to shift to Gorilla REPL as the main tool for the first talks. Thus, here is the &lt;a href='http://viewer.gorilla-repl.org/view.html?source=github&amp;user=clojure-data-science-course&amp;repo=examples&amp;path=src/examples/scraping_wikipedia.clj'&gt;wikipedia scraping example&lt;/a&gt;, translated into a Gorilla notebook (with some minor changes).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;During the course we will create more of these example notebooks &amp;ndash; you can look them up at the &lt;a href='https://github.com/clojure-data-science-course/examples'&gt;example github repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;&lt;a href='https://www.meetup.com/Clojure-Israel/events/256159018/'&gt;Meeting B1&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#95;-&amp;#95;nov&amp;#95;28th&amp;#95;2018&quot;&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.meetup.com/Clojure-Israel/events/256159018/'&gt;Meeting B1&lt;/a&gt; - Nov 28th 2018&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was the first meeting of &lt;strong&gt; Group B&lt;/strong&gt; - data science for clojurians.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The meeting began with a light introduction for Clojure, and then everybody introduced themselves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then we continued in a similar manner to the other group's meeting, with some less attention to the example though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the end, we had some overview of some relevant clojure libraries and topics that we may dive into during the course. See  the &lt;a href='http://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://github.com/clojure-data-science-course/talks/blob/master/talk1/talk.html'&gt;presentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>
Sat, 15 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0200
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<guid>
http://https://clojure-data-science-course.github.io/posts-output/2018-12-11-towards-the-second-meeting/
</guid>
<link>
http://https://clojure-data-science-course.github.io/posts-output/2018-12-11-towards-the-second-meeting/
</link>
<title>
Towards the Second Meeting
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;Next week we will have the second meeting for the two groups. This time, it will be about &lt;strong&gt;machine learning&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group A&lt;/strong&gt; - clojure for data scientists - &lt;a href='https://www.meetup.com/Clojure-Israel/events/257088858/'&gt;Meeting A2&lt;/a&gt; - Dec 16th 2018d&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Group B&lt;/strong&gt; - data science for clojurians - &lt;a href='https://www.meetup.com/Clojure-Israel/events/257089002/'&gt;Meeting B2&lt;/a&gt; - Dec 19th 2018&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;preparing&amp;#95;for&amp;#95;the&amp;#95;meeting&quot;&gt;Preparing for the meeting&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you like to play during the meeting, it is recommended to come with a laptop, after installing Git, Java &amp; Leiningen. It is also recommended to play at home with Gorilla-REPL, and get used to it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href='../../pages-output/software/'&gt;Software&lt;/a&gt; section for details, and please tell if you have any trouble installing anything.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;agenda&quot;&gt;Agenda&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id=&quot;backround&quot;&gt;Backround&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the first hour we will have some background material.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;On group A, we will continue the introduction to the language - you can skip it if you are a clojurian.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;On group B, Alik Peltinovitch will give a general introduction to machine learning - you can skip it if you are an experienced data scientist.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h4 id=&quot;demo&quot;&gt;Demo&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the main part of the meeting, we will solve together a practical machine learning problem in clojure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4 id=&quot;would&amp;#95;you&amp;#95;like&amp;#95;to&amp;#95;talk&amp;#95;about&amp;#95;anything?&quot;&gt;Would you like to talk about anything?&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some of you have already started looking into personal projects. Maybe wish to share your thoughts with the group. Or maybe you saw some interesting library, or had some question you were curious about. This is a great opportunity to share with the group.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let us discuss it before the meeting, so we can adjust the timing a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4 id=&quot;discussion&quot;&gt;Discussion&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Towards, we will discuss our plans for the next meetings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>
Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0200
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<guid>
http://https://clojure-data-science-course.github.io/posts-output/2018-12-05-homework-for-the-first-meeting/
</guid>
<link>
http://https://clojure-data-science-course.github.io/posts-output/2018-12-05-homework-for-the-first-meeting/
</link>
<title>
Homework for the First Meeting
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;Thanks and greetings to everybody who has joined the course!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the first meetings of the two groups we met two magnificent teams of people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The beginning may have been challenging to some of us &amp;ndash; coming from several different mindsets and realizing that together through the conversation. Let us remember that confusion is part of what we expect to experience when we encounter new ideas. Thanks, everybody, for keeping a warm and kind dialogue through the meetings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Soon we will upload the materials from the meetings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To prepare for the next meetings, we suggest the following.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Install Gorilla REPL and play with it. See the &lt;a href='../../pages-output/software/'&gt;Software&lt;/a&gt; section.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Read &lt;a href='http://viewer.gorilla-repl.org/view.html?source=github&amp;user=lspector&amp;repo=clojinc&amp;path=worksheet.clj'&gt;clojinc&lt;/a&gt; by Lee Spector. Copy some parts to your Gorilla REPL, and play.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Choose 5 problems from &lt;a href='http://www.4clojure.com/problems'&gt;4Clojure&lt;/a&gt;, and try to solve them. If you do something interesting, share &lt;a href='https://clojurians.zulipchat.com/#narrow/stream/152323-data-science-course-tlv'&gt;at our Zulip stream&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Start reading chapters 1,3,4,5,(6 if you wish),9,11,12 at Daniel Higginbotham's &lt;a href='https://www.braveclojure.com/clojure-for-the-brave-and-true/'&gt;Clojure for the Brave and True&lt;/a&gt;. Copy some parts to your Gorilla REPL, and play. It is ok if you do not complete this before the next meeting.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Watch some &lt;a href='http://gorilla-repl.org/videos.html'&gt;videos&lt;/a&gt; about Gorilla REPL.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Let us talk, to share our thoughts.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>
Wed, 05 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0200
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<guid>
http://https://clojure-data-science-course.github.io/posts-output/2018-12-04-hello/
</guid>
<link>
http://https://clojure-data-science-course.github.io/posts-output/2018-12-04-hello/
</link>
<title>
Hello
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the course blog!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please read carefully into the pages in the navigation bar. Your thoughts and comments will be welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>
Tue, 04 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0200
</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
